Joseph Kerkhof

□ +1 920 376 1248 | ② joseph@kerkhof.dev | ۞ GitHub | ③ Portfolio | ♥ Cecil, WI

Summary

A full-stack software engineer with extensive experience in developing practical, appropriately scaled solutions within collaborative, diverse teams. Equipped with a keen ability to build solutions that effectively minimize technical debt, consistently delivering high-quality code and maintainable software systems.

EDUCATION

University of Wisconsin — Oshkosh

M.Sc. in Data Science; **GPA:** 4.00/4.00

B.Sc. in Computer Science

Oshkosh West High School

High School Diploma

Oshkosh, WI

Sept 2017 - Jun 2021 Sept 2011 - Jun 2016

Oshkosh, WI

Sept 2009 - Jun 2011

Work Experience

Prodege Remote, USA

PHP Developer

Mar 2023 - Current

- Refactored and upgraded PHP cron jobs and their dependencies leveraging modern Laravel and external APIs
 resulting in improved reliability to critical business functions.
- Implemented the Google Ads SDK for internal tools, streamlining the process of creating campaigns, ad groups, keywords, and ads, resulting in a significant reduction in workflow friction.
- Streamlined MySQL queries and improved table design for large datasets (tables in the hundreds of GBs), resulting in enhanced performance and efficiency.

Clockwork Minneapolis, MN

Senior Software Engineer

Mar 2019 - Mar 2023

- Led the development and deployment of new web products using React, Typescript, and Jest unit tests as team scrum master.
- Develop cloud-native apps on AWS using modern tools like Rust, TypeScript.
- Developed software maintenance plans and automation tools to sustainably and regularly reduce technology debt and automate repetitive, time-consuming tasks.
- Load-tested a high-performance website to find bottlenecks in the application and infrastructure layers and remediate them.
- Maintained a proprietary promotion engine powering >350K customer accounts with thousands of daily interactions using PHP.

University of Wisconsin — Oshkosh

Oshkosh, WI

Web Developer

 $May\ 2016-Mar\ 2019$

- Championed a migration of disparate Plone websites to a standardized WordPress Multisite on AWS.
- Led a team of 15 Computer Science student developers in design, programming, and standardization of MVC web-based applications using the .NET framework.

Affiliations & Volunteering

Thorn Data Science Hackathon (2019): Created tools for CSAM detection using natural language processing libraries.

Judge at Minnesota Technovation (2019): Technovation is a global tech education non-profit that inspires girls to be leaders and problem solvers in their community.

Campus Web Council of Wisconsin (2016 — 2019)

Projects

Filters and Fractals | GitHub

- A C project which implements a variety of image processing operations that manipulate the size, filter, brightness, contrast, saturation, and other properties of PPM images from scratch.
- Added recursive fractal generation functions to model popular fractals including Mandelbrot set, Julia set, Koch curve, Barnsley fern, and Sierpinski triangle in PPM format.

SKILLS

Programming: PHP, Rust, JavaScript, TypeScript, MySQL, Shell

Technologies: Git, Linux, AWS

Frameworks: Laravel, React, Jest, Tailwind, Bootstrap